Finding Aid for Fred Hammond collection.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Fred Hammond collection 1957-1992 1950s-1960s
Hammond, Fred
0.5 linear feet in 3 boxes (boxes 2 and 3 are outsize)
2014100 Aa 2
Collection consists of photographs taken by photographer Fred Hammond for use by the Michigan Department of Transportation and personal photos.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
This collection was donated by Joyce Hammond (donor number 10955 ) in three accessions, between June 2013 and May 2014.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Fred Hammond was a professional photographer who worked for the Michigan Department of Transportation since the 1950s.
Mostly black-and-white photographs depict road construction, transportation, astronomy, buildings and structures, scenes of nature, severe weather, tourist scenes, portraits, photographs of the highway patrol photo shop, and photographs of the Faith Lutheran Church in Okemos, Michigan. Collection includes oversize photos of President John F. Kennedy, Governor G. Mennen Williams, and John C. Mackie who served as the Michigan State Highway Commissioner in 1957-1964. Some Michigan Department of Transportation publications, advertisements, and newspaper clippings are also included within the collection. Photographs are all in relation to the state of Michigan.
Subjects:
Michigan.--Department of Transportation.
Subject - Visual materials:
Astronomy.; Churches--Michigan.; Faith Lutheran Church (Okemos, Mich.); Michigan.--Department of Transportation.; Nature--Michigan.; Road construction--Michigan.; Tourism--Michigan.; Transportation--Michigan.
Genre/Form:
Photographs
- Fred Hammond Collection
  - Astronomy, undated and 1957 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and structures, undated (Box 1)
  - Construction, 1958-1960 (Box 1)
  - Highway patrol photo shop pictures, 1984 and undated (Box 1)
  - Photos from Faith Lutheran Church, 1964 and undated (Box 1)
  - Programs and publications, 1957-1964 (Box 1)
  - Scenes of nature, undated (Box 1)
  - Severe weather, undated (Box 1)
  - Tourist scenes, undated (Box 1)
  - Transportation, undated and 1962 (Box 1)
  - Buildings and structures, undated and 1963 (Box 2)
  - Construction, undated (Box 2)
  - Michigan Department of Transportation publications, 1978-1992 (Box 2)
  - Portraits, undated (Box 3)
  - Scenes of nature, undated (Box 3)
  - Tourist scenes, undated (Box 3)
  - Transportation, undated (Box 3)